SATHISH S

2550 Ubhur stree, Almalga, Riyadh, Saudi arabia (+966) 0583778952

sa.sathish@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sathish-s-b498a058/

Over 5+ years of experience in the area of native iOS application development Using Objective c, Swift, SwiftUI. which includes understanding requirement specification, working on software design, coding, testing and maintenance. Knowledge of professional software engineering practices and best practices for the full software development life cycle, including coding standards, code reviews, source control management, build processes, testing, and operations.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TECHNOLOGY CONTROL COMPANY,

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia August 2021–Present

Application developer

- Designed user experience frameworks applicable to fit both iPad and iPhone screens
- Was involved in Usability testing of the application during early releases of the application to modify any user experience elements to be changed.

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia **TAWARI TECHNOLOGY**

iOS Developer

Jan 2020- July 2021

- Implemented CryptoJS encryption to the existing project
- Established compatibility with third party software products by developing programming for modifications and integrations

CASPERON TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD

Chennai, Tamilnadu

iOS Developer - Trainee

Dec 2016-Nov 2019

- Correct errors by making appropriate changes and rechecking the program to ensure that the desired results are
- Proposed technical feasibility solutions for new functional designs and suggested options for performance improvement of technical objects.

EDUCATION

PR ENGINEERING COLLEGE - ANNA UNIVERSITY

Thanjavur, Tamilnadu

Jun 2015

Master of computer application (MCA) Aggregate: Cumulative GPA: 7.65

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- Objective-C
- Swift
- SwiftUI

FRAMEWORKS

- **UIKit**
- Combain
- Cocoa Touch
- **RXSwift**
- CocoaPods

DEPENDENCY

- Socket.io
- WebRTC
- **Firebase**
- RealmSwift
- MessageKit

TOOLS

- **XCode**
- Git/Gitlab
- Trello

PROJECTS

Project 1: ZerveX

Role: iOS Developer

iTunes: User - https://apps.apple.com/us/app/zervx-all-service-in-one-app/id1564689086?platform=iphone
Deriver - https://apps.apple.com/us/app/zervx-driver-all-in-one-app/id1564865190?platform=iphone

Technologies Used: Swift, iOS SDK, XCode 12, Cocoa Touch frameworks, RealmSwift, CocoaPods, Socket.io, Git.

- Transportation Application. users can book the taxis nearby their areas.
- User can message to driver.

Project 2: LIXR

Role: iOS Developer

iTunes: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/lixr/id1445993905

Technologies Used: Swift, iOS SDK, XCode 10, iPhone Simulators, Cocoa Touch frameworks, CocoaPods, QR Code Reader, MapKit API integration, GIT, Gesture Recognition, RESTFUL Web Services, JSON Parser.

- LIXR is a Social platform to connect with everyone and can share the events and posts with public and friends.
- Finally, the Digital supports the Real social moments!! Connect with Like minded friends and enjoy the Lixr experience in almost every popular Hangout in your City.

Project 3: SCIMBO

Role: iOS Developer

iTunes: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/scimbo/id1241913262

Technologies Used: Swift, iOS SDK, XCode 10, Cocoa Touch frameworks, CocoaPods, WebRTC, Socket.io, GIT.

- Scimbo is an advanced real-time messaging/calling application.
- The users can send videos, images, text messages, gif and audio messages, share locations, share contacts, send documents via Scimbo.
- Using Scimbo user could make video/audio call to friends and family for free.

Project 4: TRUZTPRO

Role: iOS Developer

iTunes: User - https://apps.apple.com/us/app/truztpro/id1354294771

Craftsman - https://apps.apple.com/us/app/truztpro-craftsman/id1354294992

Technologies Used: Swift, iOS SDK, XCode 9, Cocoa Touch frameworks, CocoaPods, Socket.io, RESTFUL Web Services, JSON Parser

- On-demand handyman services. Easy to find workers.
- Clean facilities by sweeping, dusting etc.
- Perform maintenance and light repairs.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the above information are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Date: SATHISH S